

LIAM NOLAN

MECHATRONICS ENGINEER

CONTACT

Email

liamjosephnolan@gmail.com

Phone

+43 67761089511

Address

Dr. Stumpf Straße 102 6020 Innsbruck, Austria

SKILLS

- SolidWorks
- Python
- MATLAB
- Simulink
- C Programming
- Autodesk Inventor
- Mastercam
- 3D Printing
- DFMEA
- CNC Manufacturing

LANGUAGES

English - Native

German - Beginner

ABOUT ME

I am a Mechanical/Mechatronics Engineer with four years of industry experience in the medical device field. I am pursuing a Master's degree in Mechatronics at MCI. I am passionate about Mechanical Design, Robotics, and Control Engineering.

Date of birth: May 14, 1997

Place of birth: Seattle, United States of America

WORK EXPERIENCE

Mechanical Engineer

August 2019 - March 2023

Ethicon Inc. (J&J Medical Devices) - Santa Clara, CA

- Project Lead of Mechanical Immobilization solution for surgeon console
- Team Lead of capital equipment packaging project
- Designed and integrated robotic subsystems for the Surgeon Console
- Designed and coordinated manufacturing of PCB and optical test fixtures
- Coordinated repair efforts for surgical robotic systems in Clinical setting
- Supported procedure development efforts in surgical labs

Mechanical Engineering Intern

June 2018 - September 2018

Auris Health Inc. - Redwood City, CA

- Designed and manufactured custom electromechanical actuator to immobilize surgical system
- Assembled, tested, and characterized performance of multi-axis robotic arms
- Tuned, characterized, and tested custom electromechanical actuator
- Analyzed assembly critical tolerance stackups in custom actuator assemblies
- Created, reviewed, and delivered part drawings for manufacture

Mechanical Engineering Intern

June 2017 - September 2017

Orbital ATK - Goleta, California

- Prototyped assembly methods for various satellite deployables
- Assembled and tested engineering development units
- Analyzed flight hardware for defects and insured assemblies were within

CV - Liam Nolan 1/2

tolerance

- Manufactured and assembled stiffness and thermal test fixtures

Mechanical Engineering Intern June 2016 - September 2016

Breedt Production Tooling and Design - Kent, Washington

- Design, manufactured, and tested large scale industrial tooling
- Responsible for mechanical and electrical design of robotic hydroponic foam cutter
- Designed and manufactured six plate rubber compression mold stripper

Mechanical Engineering Intern June 2015 - September 2015

Breedt Production Tooling and Design - Kent, Washington

- Designed and manufactured parts for external customers
- Operated and maintained both CNC manufacturing equipment and manual machining equipment

EDUCATION

Master's degree

2023 - present

MCI, Mechatronics - Innsbruck, Austria

Bachelor's Degree

2015 - 2019

California Polytechnic State University, Aerospace Engineering - San Luis Obispo

FIRST ROBOTICS

- Student of FRC team 2046 (2012-2015)

Club President

- Mentor of FRC team 973 (2017 & 2018)

2017 World Champions

BATTLEBOTS

- -Engineer for Alexis (3lb combat robot)
- -Engineer for Zenith (250lb combat robot)

CV - Liam Nolan 2/2